<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essay on D U N K</title>
    <link>https://nikodunk.com/tags/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essay on D U N K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nikodunk.com/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for the next decade</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/predictions-for-the-next-decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/predictions-for-the-next-decade/</guid>
      <description>Google will be replaced as the up-and-coming search engine by DuckDuckGo, as starting today I&#39;ve switched to them full-time and feel no need to go back. They have more developer mindshare. Possibly also Facebook and Apple who have been running on fumes for a while but I am less sure there. Their core products are not actively being made worse at the rate that Google&#39;s is. Manufacturing, and having it close-by, will become increasingly important again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thought: Gillets Jaunes sounds like russian</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/thought-gillets-jaunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/thought-gillets-jaunes/</guid>
      <description>Glad to read this, after a few weeks of wondering how the Gillets Jaunes movement in France could organize through Facebook Groups yet no-one was drawing the parallels to the last time social unfairness was harnessed by a foreign power to turn out mass-protests. Apparently there&#39;s no smoke to that fire.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: As cities grow, nations will fade.</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/cities/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted at swissnex San Francisco as Back to the city
 Democracy was designed for the city 54% of the world&#39;s population now lives in cities, and more humans move to urban areas every day. But with voters and power concentrated in metropolitan areas, are nations holding cities back?
Democracy was designed to rule a city, after all – Athens. Maybe we&#39;ve stretched the democratic system further than it was meant to be expanded?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: Vipassana Meditation</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/vipassana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/vipassana/</guid>
      <description>A silent 10-day crash course in Buddha’s own technique. Introduction Global Vipassana Pagoda, Mumbai by Flickr user Abhishek Thakur
On my last day in Mumbai, India, I randomly visited the Global Pagoda, a gigantic structure (the largest of its kind) still under construction, rising like a giant spaceship over the wetlands north of the city. Expecting ostentation, I found a surprisingly secular take on a promise otherwise reserved only for religion, paraphrased: We want to end suffering by teaching everyone a technique to avoid the ups and downs of every day life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: The Chicago Public Library</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/chicago/</guid>
      <description>“The very existence of libraries affords the best evidence that we may yet have hope for the future of man” — T.S. Eliot  This quote is engraved in the wall of the Chicago Public Library, which is the largest public library anywhere. Here, citizens have unlimited access to the all the information they could ever want — internet, books and news. In here, information seems democratised and free for all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: No</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/no/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/no/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes saying &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; is the most positive thing to do. When do we say no? Saying no is an incredibly useful tool to weed out random or subpar options, to actively strive towards an absolute goal instead of being reactive to the noise around us. Naturally, a process of negating what you don’t want can only begin once you know what you want. Counterintuitively, the only way to find out what you want is often by saying yes to everything and gathering experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: On putting in the hours</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/hours/</guid>
      <description>Contrary to our cultural belief in natural talents, popular science is catching on to the idea that the path to success may be linear. And it may require no more than hard work.
The claim (most popularized by Malcolm Gladwell&#39;s Outliers) is that there&#39;s no such thing as a natural talent - talents are achieved through hard work, and it is never too late for anyone to start down that path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Essay: Up!</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/up/</guid>
      <description>A simple solution to high rents and long commutes in cities was invented a century ago: building up. But San Francisco is restricted vertically to an extreme degree. Why? It’s not seismic issues, it’s a density limit called Prop M. Why do we limit our cities vertically in this way?
The need for horizontal restraint is obvious: Society needs to define streetscapes, block sizes and green areas to decompress in. Building codes were established to bring some discipline into the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>