<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Essay on D U N K</title>
    <link>https://nikodunk.com/tags/essay/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Essay on D U N K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikodunk.com/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How a unified tech stack helps our tiny team punch above its weight</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/2022-05-10-the-tech-stack-for-maximum-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/2022-05-10-the-tech-stack-for-maximum-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>The stack described below has helped Atmos grow to 10,000+ customers with only 1-2 full-time-equivalent engineers. We&amp;rsquo;ve stayed secure and iterated rapidly thanks to it. Our engineering team is 10-20x leaner than our closest competitors, so we need to be 10-20x more efficient to compete.
We mainly stay efficent by reducing mental overhead and reducing maintenance burden. Our products are numerous - web, ios, android, loans, server, jobs - and yet a single developer should be able to understand, maintain and add value to all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Node to Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/a-node-js-developer-discovers-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/a-node-js-developer-discovers-rails/</guid>
      <description>I learned to code in the Javascript stack [1] and am building a Javascript based product [2]. I never questioned this stack: many companies default to it, JS everywhere seems good, and the community is big. But for my new side project I decided to try Rails because despite some perception that Ruby on Rails is ‘over’, people in HN comments say it was somehow more enjoyable than the newer Node based stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 hot takes at the beginning of 2020</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/predictions-for-the-next-decade/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/predictions-for-the-next-decade/</guid>
      <description>Google will be replaced at an ever increasing rate, probably by DuckDuckGo. I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to them full-time for the 3rd or 4th time, but this time feel no need to go back. DuckDuckGo has all the developer mindshare, and their growth is exponential. Already I&amp;rsquo;ve seen people do images search on Instagram instead of Google Images, and young people search Snapchat for recipes instead of Google. (Note from 2022: TikTok seems to be doing this) Manufacturing, and having it close by, will become increasingly important again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As cities grow, nations will fade.</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/cities/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted at swissnex San Francisco as Back to the city
 Democracy was designed for the city 54% of the world&amp;rsquo;s population now lives in cities, and more humans move to urban areas every day. But with voters and power concentrated in metropolitan areas, are nations holding cities back?
Democracy was designed to rule a city, after all – Athens. Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ve stretched the democratic system further than it was meant to be expanded?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vipassana Meditation</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/vipassana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/vipassana/</guid>
      <description>A silent 10-day crash course in Buddha’s own technique. Introduction Global Vipassana Pagoda, Mumbai by Flickr user Abhishek Thakur
On my last day in Mumbai, India, I randomly visited the Global Pagoda, a gigantic structure (the largest of its kind) still under construction, rising like a giant spaceship over the wetlands north of the city. Expecting ostentation, I found a surprisingly secular take on a promise otherwise reserved only for religion, paraphrased: We want to end suffering by teaching everyone a technique to avoid the ups and downs of every day life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/no/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/no/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes saying &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; is the most positive thing to do. When do we say no? Saying no is an incredibly useful tool to weed out random or subpar options, to actively strive towards an absolute goal instead of being reactive to the noise around us. Naturally, a process of negating what you don’t want can only begin once you know what you want. Counterintuitively, the only way to find out what you want is often by saying yes to everything and gathering experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On putting in the hours</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/hours/</guid>
      <description>Contrary to our cultural belief in natural talents, popular science is catching on to the idea that the path to success may be linear. And it may require no more than hard work.
The claim (most popularized by Malcolm Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s Outliers) is that there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as a natural talent - talents are achieved through hard work, and it is never too late for anyone to start down that path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up!</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/up/</guid>
      <description>A simple solution to high rents and long commutes in cities was invented a century ago: building up. But San Francisco is restricted vertically to an extreme degree. Why? It’s not seismic issues, it’s a density limit called Prop M. Why do we limit our cities vertically in this way?
The need for horizontal restraint is obvious: Society needs to define streetscapes, block sizes and green areas to decompress in. Building codes were established to bring some discipline into the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
