<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How-To on D U N K</title>
    <link>https://nikodunk.com/tags/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How-To on D U N K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nikodunk.com/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Patent NA25396 – A better method to transport a surfboard on a bike</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/surboard-on-bike-without-rack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/surboard-on-bike-without-rack/</guid>
      <description>The problem I live in San Francisco, and our city beach is exactly 4.7 miles away from my apartment in Haight (yay!). It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful bike ride, but it&amp;rsquo;s slightly far than I can carry my board under my arm on my bike (boo), and so far if I wanted to go surf I&amp;rsquo;d either have to rely on my friend Jake (who has a car) to also go right now, or take the N-Line on Muni which is unreliable (especially on weekends) (boo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How-to: Blockchain experiments: Software that cannot die</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>A note on technical legacy What is lasting in the tech world? Architects build things that stay forever. Technologists build things that a week later doesn&amp;rsquo;t work because npm install&amp;rsquo;s libraries have changed. I read once that the average lifespan of a webpage on the internet is 8 months. The oldest software companies are Apple and Microsoft. Legacy in software is bad. It is a dirty word.
Blockchain, because it is shared by all, may be a solution to this issue of splitting useful (but ephemeral) &amp;ldquo;built&amp;rdquo; software projects from capitalistic cycles, and allow them to be guaranteed to be run forever, as everyone is running them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How-to: $200 solar self-sufficiency — without your landlord noticing.</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/solarselfsufficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/solarselfsufficiency/</guid>
      <description>Building a solar micro-grid in my bedroom with parts from Amazon Originally posted on Hackernoon/Medium. See newest updates at sunboxlabs.com
The problem Apartment renters need the landlord’s permission to install anything on their rooftops. This makes installing solar difficult for people who rent. Because most of the world lives in urbanized areas where renting is common, I think this is a problem standing in the way of solar adoption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>