<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Updates on D U N K</title>
    <link>https://nikodunk.com/tags/updates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Updates on D U N K</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikodunk.com/tags/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>August 2020 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-20/</guid>
      <description>Dear Reader,
Sunboxlabs update – everything else unchanged (though got press for energylollipop but still have no business model and electrade is slowly growing in revenue).
Sunboxlabs: I&amp;rsquo;m a little stuck right now tbh. The early 10 customers love it and are using it for learning about solar, backup, camping.
Now I&amp;rsquo;m trying to re-create the early sales success and am testing different channels:
 Tried building SEO content, Instagram paid Ads, Twitter paid Ads, twitter unpaid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June/July 2020 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-19/</guid>
      <description>Dear Reader,
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that I&amp;rsquo;m going to start simply posting my updates as by posting (lightly edited) emails I&amp;rsquo;ve written to founder friends on my progress. This way I save time, can post more often, and I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a more authentic update anyway.
Sorry for no update! Covid hit so we interrupted fundraising and started building and getting deals with local utilities (aka CCAs) while we were waiting, and then Katie got pulled off with her kid (single mother).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings: Projects &amp; things I&#39;ve made so far.</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>This is a general blog post on my various schemes so far, roughly sorted by revenue / success. I look like this when I&amp;rsquo;ve made something:
Startups  sunboxlabs.com v2 | Self-Install Solar Kits for backup generation, etc Tested on hacker news, and sold $4.5K of goods in a few days. Then sold an addional $1.5K over the next few weeks on Instagram ads to prove that is is a scalable business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/mobile/</guid>
      <description>Electrade | A mobile marketplace for EVs ♜ Challenge: Mobile Marketplace for Electric Vehicle Leasing and Trading. Large, complex app with Stripe integration, photo upload and async operations
⚑ Solution: A simple app structure was shipped to multiple platforms and iterated on daily.
Team: * Armin (ideation, ops) * Niko (ideation, tech) Tech: * React Native on iOS &amp;amp; Android * Backend Node/Express/Postgres * Stripe payment processing * Listing photos upload to S3 * Dynamic pricing data indexed from Autotrader, Edmunds with Puppeteer * EV News updates through APIfy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2020 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-18/</guid>
      <description>Team:   Katie Patrick. Myself  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Featured in Climatetech VC 2/50 sales calls. $140K deals in pipeline., DMd 200 potential leads on LinkedIn. 20/20 product onboarding / feedback calls  Product:  Improved Chrome extension  Added (Progressive Web) App.   Experiments/Hypothesis run:  Found new possible revenue avenue: electrification. CCAs earn 3-4cents per kwh net revenue per increased sales. We can push people towards electrification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March/April 2020 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-17/</guid>
      <description>Team:   Katie Patrick. Myself  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Built next-gen product, integrated with PG&amp;amp;E 28 alpha testers of next-gen Chrome extension (see below). Hand-onboarded in 1-hour Zoom user interview sessions with screen capture. 721 followers of original Twitter bot now. 185 users of original California Chrome extension / Firefox Add-on now. $0 revenue, but 1x $70K energy innovation contract, 2x $5K energy efficiency contracts in pipeline (B2B) DM&amp;rsquo;d 900 users on Twitter, 200 on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2020 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-16/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back after a short hold for some contracting (to refresh the coffers). Now with a new project (with a refreshed mind). I have a new team, new project, but same mission – to fight global warming!
Premise: We believe that most people working in energy, solar, and climate change have been making a big mistake — that money, fear, and kilowatt-hours motivate people.
We have a different hypothesis.
Based on deep behavioral research, we discovered that people are more motivated to save energy and install solar when they see data in the form of CO2 — and the message needs to be simple: one number, one color, in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-12/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   Talked to Patrick from Byteryde.com, and shared some experiences on our different takes on the same idea of solving EV / Tesla insurance.  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Revenue: $340 Marketing Spend: $30.43 on Reddit (working! But limited.)  Product:  Did contracting this month, so put in no active marketing or blogging on hold. Nevertheless, starting to rank on first page for keywords like &amp;ldquo;Tesla Insurance Review&amp;rdquo; et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-11/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   Suhas &amp;amp; Armin now advisors. Brad now helping out with marketing.  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Revenue: $315 Marketing Spend: $160  Product:  Getting insurance agency license for California so can  keep traffic on platform and get better attribution optimize purchase / comparison experience with less data get recurring commission talk to new providers who only deal with agents   Adding more states through clearcover (AZ, TX, and more) before the end of the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-10/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   Suhas Ghante now full-time co-founder. Armin now an advisor.  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Quotes completed Goal: 110 / week Quotes completed actual: 16 / week Revenue: $335 Marketing Spend: $153  Product:  Possible other integrations Working on getting licensed as insurance broker in California or partnering with one. Trying to work out which channels scalable: Blog, Flyers, Facebook, Google marketing Thinking about re-imbursing customers for miles driven on Autopilot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-9/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   Working with Armin now. Calls every other day, text continuously. Collaborating w/ Suhas Ghante on other projects, but then increasingly electrade.  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Revenue: $360 (plus additional $120)  Product:  After initial demand from users last month for better, cheaper EV insurance (but not being able to satisfy that demand with traditional auto agents), we found an insurance API partner at the end of last month and started the integration process with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-8/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   Armin on board now. He&amp;rsquo;s still at his full-time role for now.  Calls every other day Texts throughout the day    KPIs/Core Metrics:  Revenue: $1.99  Product:  EV Insurance Experiment. Success: there is demand. Fail: Couldn&amp;rsquo;t beat prices with traditional agent network. Now integrating with Clearcover API to automate quote requests. Other bet: Positivity Trainer  Experiments/Hypothesis run:   Test Landing Page for EV Insurance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-7/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   Working with Armin now. Calls every other day, text continuously. Talked to another potential cofounder. Not as interested in this project.  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Revenue: $0 Got out of building: Every single day.  Product:  Added polish Made up-front reservation fee default. Clearer to test value for now. Tested test-drives Removed insurance Added value-add club  Found out NIO is doing the same things Found out Carmiq is doing the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-6/</guid>
      <description>Help Wanted/Asks:  Need office space (update: found in Node U) Need cofounders (update: trial)  Hiring:   Candidates in hiring funnel for cofounder: 14 Interviews: 2 Trial running with cofounder (Armin)  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Monthly Active Users: 270 Weekly Active Users: 100 Daily Active Users: 13-40 Lease requests: 12 Lease requests per day: 1-2 Lease conversions: 0 Lease conversion revenue: $0  Product:  Added weekly LEASE deals scraped from ev-vin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-5/</guid>
      <description>This month has been mostly resetting on a new project, electrade. I&amp;rsquo;ve been interviewing a bunch of EV owners over the phone to ask for problems, and going to a Golden Gate Electric Vehicle Meetup.
Not much to update on this month. Tracking WAU – 20% week over week growth but at this scale it means nothing.
Help Wanted/Asks:  N/A  Hiring:   N/A  KPIs/Core Metrics:  Monthly Active Users: 50 Weekly Active Users: 20 Daily Active Users: 5-10 Posts: 0 Revenue: $0  Experiments/Hypothesis run:  Electric Vehicle News app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-4/</guid>
      <description>After 4 months of working on healthcare stuffs and nearly making it (we signed a first deal of $600/mo, but then couldn&amp;rsquo;t deliver an external integration they needed UGH) I have to face the decision to double down again or reset. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to reset to something more in line with my natural interests: I&amp;rsquo;ve now been working for the past couple weeks on the (first) electric vehicle marketplace app. &amp;ldquo;Find a used tesla near me&amp;rdquo; – screenshot attached :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2019 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-3/</guid>
      <description>We just signed up our first paying customer here at Paperwork Labs, so it&amp;rsquo;s time for the January update. See last month&amp;rsquo;s here – TLDR; December: New cofounder, MVP, Received Grant from Emergent Ventures, Pivot from solving medical note-taking to solving medical paperwork. We are now building &amp;ldquo;Turbotax for Medical Forms&amp;rdquo;.
KPIs  We are default dead Paying customers: 1 MRR: $600 Net MRR growth: 1800% (from $31.92 MRR for soapdictate ;)) Customer churn: 0% Team: 2 people Cash: $37,500 in bank Monthly burn: $2,500  Key Events Good  Sales/Customer-Month: We&amp;rsquo;ve talked to 5 practice groups this month, added a 6th group today alone, and have signed up one practice from the largest group for X licenses (X * $99).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December 2018 Startup Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-2/</guid>
      <description>Month 2: Still laser-focused on writing code and talking to users, but now have found a good potential co-founder, brainstormed a new, bigger problem with him (important!) and received some initial grant funding to take some of the financial risk off my back.
Week 5  Could not grow further and missed growth targets again – started investing time into overhauling sunboxlabs.com and a completely new energy app idea. Finally got LLC paperwork and Azlo account from the Stripe Atlas incorporation, and switching app store ownership, sunboxlabs income and soapdictate income to it – seperating church and state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2018 Startup Update: Month 1</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-1/</guid>
      <description>Month 1: Lazer-like focused on writing code and talking to users. After Elisa and I split up from doing giftlab.io, I decided to focus on soapdictate after I&amp;rsquo;d left swissnexSF. soapdictate is my other side-project, and I wanted to see if I could make it work. I left swissnexSF October 31st 2018 and switched to working on the soapdictate dictation app full-time.
Week 1  quickly followed up with all contacts from job to let them know what i&amp;rsquo;m working on incorporated LLC with stripe atlas (more like aside project currently but don&amp;rsquo;t want liability), Did health insurance, worked from friends&amp;rsquo; office.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
