<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Updates on D U N K | niko&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://nikodunk.com/tags/updates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Updates on D U N K | niko&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nikodunk.com/tags/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from projects &amp; things I&#39;ve made so far.</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>This is a general blog post on my various schemes so far, loosely grouped around topic. I look like this when I&amp;rsquo;ve made something:
Sustainability electrade app | Premium services for Electric Cars Team: * Amir (ideation, ops) * Niko (ideation, tech) Tech: * React-Native App * Backend Node/Express/Postgres * Stripe payment processing * Listing photos upload to S3 * Dynamic pricing data indexed from Autotrader, Edmunds with Puppeteer * EV News updates through APIfy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December 2018 Update</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-2/</guid>
      <description>Month 2: Still laser-focused on writing code and talking to users, but now have found a good potential co-founder, brainstormed a new, bigger problem with him (important!) and received some initial grant funding to take some of the financial risk off my back.
Week 5  Could not grow further and missed growth targets again – started investing time into overhauling sunboxlabs.com and a completely new energy app idea. Finally got LLC paperwork and Azlo account from the Stripe Atlas incorporation, and switching app store ownership, sunboxlabs income and soapdictate income to it – seperating church and state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2018 Update: starting up</title>
      <link>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikodunk.com/startup-updates-1/</guid>
      <description>Month 1: Lazer-like focused on writing code and talking to users. After Elisa and I split up from doing giftlab.io, I decided to focus on soapdictate after I&amp;rsquo;d left swissnexSF. soapdictate is my other side-project, and I wanted to see if I could make it work. I left swissnexSF October 31st 2018 and switched to working on the soapdictate dictation app full-time.
Week 1  quickly followed up with all contacts from job to let them know what i&amp;rsquo;m working on incorporated LLC with stripe atlas (more like aside project currently but don&amp;rsquo;t want liability), Did health insurance, worked from friends&amp;rsquo; office.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>